Guide to the Liberal/Left archival studies papers, 1965-1988 MS2096
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Liberal/Left archival studies papers
1965-1988
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2096
2.5 Linear Feet
Collection contains articles, flyers, ephemera, and correspondence related to radical student organizations, socialism, and communism. The material dates from 1965-88 with the bulk of the material falling between 1968-71.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by an unknown person.
Historical or Biographical Note
Collection includes primary and secondary source material related to radical student organizations, socialism, and communism.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains articles, flyers, ephemera, and correspondence. The material dates from 1965-88 with the bulk of the material falling between 1968-71.
Collection Organization
Organized into two series: Newspaper articles and Pamphlets and paraphernalia.
Collection note
Please note: this collection may have been donated by Martin K. Gordon
College students -- America -- Political activity; Nineteen sixties -- United States -- Washington (D.C.); Student movements; Radicals
- Documents, 1965-1988; MS2096 Series 1; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 2, Box 3, Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains newspaper articles, correspondence, pamphlets, flyers and handouts. This material dates from 1965-88. The topics covered include the New York City High School Teacher's Strike, campus unrest, radicalism, Washington Area Free University, Non-violent direct action, the Nulcear Weapons Freeze Act, and Washington Peace Center.
  - Documents, undated (Box 1)
    General note
  - Civil Disobedience Show Love The Milwaukee Journal Thurs. Congressional Record-House, 11/19/1965-04/11/1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - New York City HS Teacher's Strike, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets, newspaper clippings, and comic, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Testimony Before Congressional Committees Investigating Campus Disorders, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper articles, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - New University Conference Incl. Biblio. 3 (10/30/1969, A.S.A.) Also 1971 A.S.A Convention Literature Distribution By Nuc., 10/30/1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - College Students/09/ Radicalism/Intellectuals & Radicalism/The University Alienation, 09/1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper articles, 01/1970-05/1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - College Students/Radicalism/Intellectuals & Radicalism The University Alienation, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Documents, undated (Box 2)
  - Handouts, Posters, Broadsides, 05/1970-07/1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper articles, 06/1970-08/1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - WAFU. Tin Drum Vol. 11 No. 3 Washington Area Free University, 07/1970-08/1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper articles, 09/1970-12/1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Tsunami, Vol. 3, No. 6, 03/1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Obtained at PC PJ HQ 1029 Vermont on, 04/29/1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - May Day, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Training Manual For Nonviolent Direct Action Spring Actions, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - People for Survival People's Peace Treaty, 09/10/1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fauntroy-Chin-Lee-Hassan-Cassell Campaign Materials for D.C. delegate Nevius, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Election Board Certifies McGovern victory in D.C. "The Sunday Star" and "Daily News", 11/26/1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Rising Tide, Vol 11.No. 18, 11/06/1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Material Exclusively In/About Peace Movement, Inaugural Protest Demonstration, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Documents, undated (Box 3)
  - Earl Browder, Ex-head of Communist Party Sun-News, 06/28/1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper articles, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Workers World, Vol. 17, No. 17, 04/25/1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "The Washington Times" Vol. 1, No. 20, 09/26/1975-10/09/1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper articles, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Journals and calendars, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper articles, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper articles, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper articles, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Official Ballot: Nuclear Weapons Freeze Act of 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Washington Peace Center Newsletter Vol. 19, No. 9, 11/1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper articles, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Pamphlets and paraphernalia, undated; MS2096 Series 2; 1 Linear feet (Box 4, Box 5)
  This series contains articles, pamphlets, flyers, bumper stickers and pins. The subjects included in this series are high school radicalism, Student Democratic Society, Socialist Labor Party, communism, women's liberation movement, Young Socialist Alliance
  - High School Radicalism, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    From orignal finding aid: See Also: Citizen Participation - High Schools in Urban Problems File For Black H.S. Problems & Programs
  - Gay, Lib, Etc., undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Student Unrest, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - S.D.S. Publications and Articles, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The People's Bicentennial Comm., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Socialist labor party books and pamphlets, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Black Student Military, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Literature on Communism except huac pamphlets, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlets and paraphanalia, undated (Box 5)
  - Woman's Liberation Movements and Studies, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Young Socialist Alliance, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Book Reviews & Music Bibliographic Notes/student unrest Intellectual Radicalism, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Communist Literature W.E.B. Dubois Clubs CP USA, Red China, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Artifacts, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Magazines, flyers, and, and pamphlets, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)